Rebecca West Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, Date: 1894-1973; Series II; 4.25; (10 boxes)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Essays and Articles
      - "Is Marriage Really Breaking Up?" Evening Express (Aberdeen), 1929 Jan 16 (Box 35, Folder 1321)
      - "It Adds Up to Zero"
        See: Box 36, folder 1356
      - "It Used to Be Unladylike." Woman's Journal, 1929 May (Box 35, Folder 1322)
      - "A Jixless Errand" (wih related material). Time and Tide, 1929 Mar 15 (Box 35, Folder 1323)
      - "Labour's First Spy Trials." Sunday Telegraph (London), 1965 May 16 (Box 35, Folder 1324)
      - "Lady Without A Lamp": holograph and typescript (Box 35, Folder 1325)
      - [Lawrence, D. H.]. I Knew Him Well: A Treasury of Intimate Biographies {table of contents): typescript, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1326)
      - "Lesson of the Setty Case." Evening Citizen, 1950 Jan 27 (Box 35, Folder 1327)
      - "Lucky Boy"
        See: Box 30, folder 1240
      - "The Machinery of Buchingham Palace" (with "Housing Shortage," "Change and Cows", untitled essay on Winston Churchill, review of The Yogi and the Commissar, "The Englishman Abroad" [outline], untitled essay on William Joyce trial) (Box 35, Folder 1328)
      - "Man Who Intoxicated Us With Magical Nonsense" [Tommy Handley]. Evening Standard, 1949 Dec 1 (Box 35, Folder 1329)
      - "The Marriage Problem.", n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1330)
      - "'Meet the Intelligentsia' - Invites Rebecca West." Woman's Journal, 1929 Feb (Box 35, Folder 1331)
      - "Mr. Lewis Einstein, Diplomatist and Man of Letters" (obituary, with Henry Andrews). The Times (London) (7 copies), 1967 Dec 13 (Box 35, Folder 1332)
      - "Modern Hypocrisy About the Young Criminal." The Glasgow Herald, 1950 (Box 35, Folder 1333)
      - "My Golden Playground." The Looker-On, 1929 Mar 9 (Box 35, Folder 1334)
      - [My Most Memorable Meal]: holograph and typescript, with letter, 1957 (Box 35, Folder 1335)
      - "The Nemesis of Apartheid." The Sunday Times (London), 1960 Mar 27 (Box 35, Folder 1336)
      - "New Secular Forms of Old Religious Ideas" (with related items). The Realist, 1929 Jun (Box 35, Folder 1337)
      - "A Night of Memories and Sighs": holograph notebook (Box 35, Folder 1338)
      - "The Nonsense About The Mystery of Life." The Daily Mail, 1928 Sep 24 (Box 35, Folder 1339)
      - "Notes on the Way"
        - Holograph (mixed drafts), n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1340)
        - Time and Tide, 1949 Jul 23-30 (Box 35, Folder 1341)
      - "Nothing To Do But Die." Crewe Guardian, 1949 Jul 18 (Box 35, Folder 1342)
      - "Opera In Greenville"
        - Source material, 1944, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1343)
        - The New Yorker (reprint), 1947 (Box 36, Folder 1344)
        - News clippings (trial coverage, related events, response), 1947 (Box 36, Folder 1345-48)
        - Teletype reports (copies), 1947 (Box 36, Folder 1349)
        - Related correspondence, 1947 (Box 36, Folder 1350)
        - "A Greenville Lynch Case Lawyer Explains": typescript, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1351)
      - "The Organization of Buckingham Palace"
      - "Paris Is Just an Illusion." Evening Standard (London), 1950 Jun 9 (Box 36, Folder 1352)
      - "People Who Have Interested Me." Royal Magazine, 1928 Dec (Box 36, Folder 1353)
      - "Picasso Preface": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1354)
      - "The Poetry of 1927." T. P.'s Weekly, 1928 Jan 7 (Box 36, Folder 1355)
      - "Post-Mortem on Radio Propaganda" (with "Transatlantic Errors," "Springtime Scrapbook," "It Adds Up To Zero," untitled essays on exiles and political deportations) (Box 36, Folder 1356)
      - "Prospects in Yugoslavia" (with untitled essays on Slavic studies and languages, and William Joyce trial) (Box 36, Folder 1357)
      - "Rebecca West Answers the Question-- Are There Too Many Attractive Men?" Woman's Journal, 1928 (Box 36, Folder 1358)
      - "Rebecca West to Dean Inge." Daily Express (London) (with related articles), 1927 Nov 21 (Box 36, Folder 1359)
      - "Reflections on the English Face." The Saturday Evening Post, 1973 May-Jun (Box 36, Folder 1360)
      - "Repairing the Damage." The Author, 1962 Summer (Box 36, Folder 1361)
      - [Republican Convention]: newspaper articles, 1948 (Box 36, Folder 1362)
      - "Rosamund Ravished, but Rose Rose." Vogue, 1973 Jan (Box 36, Folder 1363)
      - "Shakespeare Lives in Pageantry for King" (incomplete): The Seattle Times, 1952 Feb 12 (Box 36, Folder 1364)
      - "Shots--and a Cry of 'Shame'." The Sunday Times (London), 1960 Apr 10 (Box 36, Folder 1365)
      - "So This Is Peace!" The New Republic, 1925 Mar 4 (Box 36, Folder 1366)
      - "Socialism in the Searchlight": newspaper clipping, 1916 Nov 6 (Box 36, Folder 1367)
      - "Society Beauties--Are Chosen by Famous Critics--and Why." Royal Magazine, 1928 (Box 36, Folder 1368)
      - "Something to Say" (radio program with script outlines and West's essays on prison reform, taexes, etc.): typescripts (Box 36, Folder 1369)
      - "Springtime Scrapbook"
      - [Spanish Civil War]. Letter to unidentified author, unpublished: typescript and carbon, 1961 Sep 11 (Box 36, Folder 1370)
      - "Stalin's Agents Got Trotsky in the End." Edinburgh Evening News, 1950 Mar 30 (Box 36, Folder 1371)
      - "Stoker Rise": holograph notebook (Box 36, Folder 1372)
        - (incomplete), n.d.
      - "Strange Interviews." Woman, 1929 Feb (Box 36, Folder 1373)
      - "There are Plastic Gnomes in Washington." The New York Times, 1973 Jul 2 (Box 37, Folder 1374)
      - "Things That Are More Important Than Sex Problems." South Wales Echo, 1929 Mar 22 (Box 37, Folder 1375)
      - "The Time Book" ("Time Flies"): holograph notebook, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1376)
      - "Transatlantic Errors"
      - "The Troubled Years" ("The Seven Ages of Women" - IV) Evening Standard (London), 1928 Mar 29 (Box 37, Folder 1377)
      - "True Womanhood." The Woman's Journal, 1927 Dec (Box 37, Folder 1378)
      - "Vassal in Secret." Sunday Telegraph (London), 1962 Nov 25 (Box 37, Folder 1379)
      - "Venice." Travel and Leisure, 1973 Jun-Jul (Box 37, Folder 1380)
      - "A Visit to My Godmother": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1381)
      - [The Wallace Convention]: news clippings, 1948 (Box 37, Folder 1382)
      - "Wendell Willkie: Where Is He Going" (with miscellaneous notes): holograph and typescripts (mixed drafts) (Box 37, Folder 1383)
      - "When Mothers Know Best." Woman's Pictorial, 1927 Oct 1 (Box 37, Folder 1384)
      - "What a Stupid Thing To Do"
        See: Box 35, folder 1215
      - "Women in Western Civilization." Newcastle Daily Journal and Courant North Star, 1929 Jan 7 (Box 37, Folder 1385)
      - "A World Where No One Is Sacked: This Can Be Terrifying." Evening Citizen (Glasgow), 1949 Jan 26 (Box 37, Folder 1386)
      - "The Young Wife." Royal Magazine, 1928 Feb (Box 37, Folder 1387)
      - "Yugoslavia Fights On" (radio play): typescript, 1942 (Box 37, Folder 1388)
      - Untitled essays, language exercises, short translations: holograph notebook, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1389)
      - Excerpts (newspaper clippings), 1927-28, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1390)
      - Fragments, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1391)
    - Reviews
      - "Books of the Day." The Daily News and Leader, 1916, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1392)
      - "Memorandum" ( Germany -- The Truth, by Reginald Garbutt): typescript (Box 37, Folder 1393)
      - "Notes on Novels." The New Statesman, 1920 (Box 37, Folder 1394)
      - Theater reviews, 1911-29 (Box 37, Folder 1395)
      - Others, 1917-73, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1396-97)
    - Other Writings
      - Letters to the editor, 1927-72 (Box 37, Folder 1398-99)
- Personal Papers, 1903-74; Series III; 1.75; (5 boxes)
  Series III, Personal Papers, is arranged alphabetically by subject in four subseries.
  - REBECCA WEST MATERIAL
    - Andrews family papers, 1903, 1915, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1400)
    - Anthony West--H. G. Wells controversy: memoranda (Box 38, Folder 1401)
    - Biographical information
      - Untitled autobiographical sketch (incomplete): typescript, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1402)
      - Autobiographical memoranda, 1958 (Box 38, Folder 1403)
    - Diaries, 1918-46 (Box 38, Folder 1404-10)
    - Financial and business papers
      - A. D. Peters, 1929-33 (Box 38, Folder 1411-14)
      - George T. Bye, 1933-38 (Box 39, Folder 1415-19)
      - J. B. Pinker (royalty statements), 1928-35 (Box 39, Folder 1420)
      - Miscellaneous, 1924-61 (Box 39, Folder 1421-22)
    - Interviews (news reports), 1929-73 (Box 39, Folder 1423)
    - Legal papers, 1928-58 (Box 39, Folder 1424-25)
    - Newspaper clippings (miscellaneous), 1928 (Box 39, Folder 1426)
    - Photographs and sketches
      See also: Oversize, Box 44, folder 1528
      - Rebecca West, 1928-38, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1427-28)
      - Others, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1429)
    - Political pamphlets, 1945-47, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1430)
    - Postcards, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1431)
    - Rebecca West Papers: notes on the collection by G. Evelyn Hutchinson, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1432)
    - "Serbian Exercises": holograph notebook, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 1433)
    - U.S. Presidential Campaign: publicity brochures, 1948 (Box 39, Folder 1434)
    - Wedding and Anniversaries: guest lists, etc., 1930, 1955 (Box 39, Folder 1435)
  - WRITINGS ABOUT REBECCA WEST
    - Davis, J. Lionberger. "Lines on Reading a Book of Rebecca West.. .": typescript, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1436)
    - Emerson, Joyce. "Rebecca West: Writer and Feminist": typescript (Box 39, Folder 1437)
    - Forbes, Rosita. "Rebecca West." Woman's Pictorial, 1929 Apr 20 (Box 39, Folder 1438)
    - Levin, Bernard. "Rebecca West: The Light That Never Failed." The Times (London), 1972 Dec 21 (Box 39, Folder 1439)
    - Ray, Gordon. H. G. Wells and Rebecca West (reviews of Lilian Hellman, Anthony West, and others), 1974 (Box 39, Folder 1440)
    - Stern, G.B. "The Clown of Parnassus." New York Herald Tribune, 1928 Sep 30 (Box 39, Folder 1441)
    - Williams, Frances Fenwick. "Notes on Horoscope of Mrs. Andrews": typescript (Box 39, Folder 1442)
    - Miscellaneous short articles, 1929, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1443)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1918-29 (Box 40, Folder 1444-53)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Andrews, Henry
      - Adenauer interview (transcript): typescript and page proofs ( London Observer ), 1949 (Box 40, Folder 1454)
      - "Aide Memoire": typescript (with related correspondence) (Box 40, Folder 1455)
      - "Bismillah and Other Journeys" (review): printed text (Box 40, Folder 1456)
      - "Central and Southeastern Europe" (Post-War Economy)
        - "Notes 1" and "Notes 2": typescripts, 1942 Jun (Box 40, Folder 1457)
        - "Introduction": typescript, 1943 Apr (Box 40, Folder 1458)
        - "Appendix 1" and "Appendix 2": typescripts (Box 40, Folder 1459)
      - "Ernst on Weizaecker" (letter to editor): newspaper clipping, 1950 (Box 40, Folder 1460)
      - "First Impressions in Germany": typescript, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1461)
      - "Jugend Unterm Schicksal": typescript (Box 40, Folder 1462)
      - "Lewis Einstein. Alori Cemetery, Florence. Friday, April 5th, 1968" (eulogy): typescript (with copy of letter from Rebecca West) (Box 40, Folder 1463)
      - "Memorandum" (post-war foreign business): typescript, 1942 Jan 15 (Box 40, Folder 1464)
      - "Note" (land reform in Germany after World War II): typescript (Box 40, Folder 1465)
      - "Note on Conversation with Dr. Gille": typescript, carbon, corrected, 1950 (Box 40, Folder 1466)
      - "Notes for Article": typescript (2 copies), [1950] (Box 40, Folder 1467)
      - "Notes on Return from Berlin": typescript (2 copies), 1933 May 13 (Box 40, Folder 1468)
      - "Notes on the Spanish Jews in Bosnia": typescript, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1469)
      - "Western Germany and European Stability": typescript and printed text (with related correspondence), 1949 (Box 40, Folder 1470)
      - Untitled essays:
        - [British industry] (transcript of speech): typescript (Box 40, Folder 1471)
        - [Health services]: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1472)
        - [Post-World War II Germany]: typescript, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1473)
        - [Soviet policy of Germany during World War II]: typescript, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1474)
        - [Trade unions]: holograph, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1475)
        - [War refugees]: typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1476)
      - Miscellaneous juvenile poetry: holograph and typescript, 1917-18, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1477)
      - Unidentified notes: holograph notebook, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1478)
      - Miscellaneous: typescripts, 1938, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1479)
    - Buckley, Julian G., Jr. (Box 41)
      - "The Federal Reserve System": typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1480)
    - Edwards, H. J.
      - "Simon Magus," etc.: typescript, [1936] (Box 41, Folder 1481)
    - Einstein, Lewis
      - Diary of Mr. Lewis Einstein: typescripts and photcopy (with related correspondence and article on Lord and Lady Churchill) (Box 41, Folder 1482-83)
      - A Diplomatist Looks Back
        - Typescript A, corrected (incomplete), n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1484-85)
        - Typescript B (incomplete), n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1486)
        - List of recipients of book, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1487)
    - Emmett, Christopher
      - Miscellaneous essays: typescripts and carbons (Box 41, Folder 1488)
    - Haley, Fred T.
      - "Civil Rights and Education" (with brief reference to Rebecca West), 1964 (Box 41, Folder 1489)
    - Hardy, Thomas
      - Wessex Tales (with caricature by H. G. Wells, letter from Hardy to Wells, and note by Rebecca West): printed text, 1917 (Box 41, Folder 1490)
    - "The Ideal Doctor": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1491)
    - "Le Chien Domestique": typescript (Box 41, Folder 1492)
    - McLachlen, Donald
      - Untitled essay on naval intelligence and submarine warfare (Box 41, Folder 1493)
    - Mead, Margaret (Box 41, Folder 1494)
      - "Letter from Montserrat: Visiting in Somebody Else's Field": typescript, 1966
    - "Memorandum Concerning the Relationship of German Incitement in Czechoslovakia to the International Colonial Problem.. .": typescript (Box 41, Folder 1495)
    - Merton, Richard
      - "About the Ruhr-Problem": typescript, carbon, 1948 Feb 25 (Box 41, Folder 1496)
      - "Falsehood in Wartime": typescript, carbon, 1947 Oct 10 (Box 41, Folder 1497)
    - Mitchison, Naomi
      - The Alban Goes Out, 1939 (Box 41, Folder 1498)
    - Morgenstern, Osker (Box 41, Folder 1499)
      - "An Economic Program for Germany": typescript, 1947 Oct 2
    - Prichard, M. S.
      - "Greek and Byzantine Art" (3 articles): typescript and printed text (Box 42, Folder 1500)
      - "Diaries. Volune X": typescript, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1501)
    - Sarton, May
      - "At Lindos" (poem): typescript (Box 42, Folder 1502)
    - Sewell, M. E.
      - "The Nature of Public Dream" (outline): typescript, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1503)
    - Stern, G. B.
      - "The Three Tragic Sisters." New York Herald Tribune. "G. B. Stern on Noel Coward": printed text (with related news clippings), 1928, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1504)
    - Waley, Arthur
      - "The One Love": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1505)
    - Wells, H. G.
      - "The World, Its Debts, and the Rich Man: A Speech by H. G. Wells": printed text, [1922] (Box 42, Folder 1506)
    - West, Anthony
      - Juvenile writings and sketches (Box 42, Folder 1507)
      - News clippings, 1950-55, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1508)
    - "What Europe Knew of China Three Hundred Years Ago" (printed text: Grabhorn printing)
      See: Oversize, Box 44, folder 1529
    - Unidentified essay on the ordination of women: typescript, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1509)
    - Unidentified poem: holograph, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1510)
    - Miscellaneous short writings, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1511)
  - OTHER PAPERS
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1915-74, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1512-15)
      See also: Oversize, Box 44, folder 1530
- Oversize, 1936-57; 3; (2 boxes)
  Oversize contains materials from the Writings and Personal Papers series, arranged in the order in which they appear in these series.
  - WRITINGS
    - The Court and the Castle
      - Plate proofs, [1957] (Box 43, Folder 1516)
      - Page proofs (marked "Duplicate Set"), [1957] (Box 43, Folder 1517-19)
      - Page proofs, corrected, [1957] (Box 43, Folder 1520-22)
      - Page proofs, revised, [1957] (Box 43, Folder 1523-25)
    - Harriet Hume
      - Holograph notebook, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1526-27)
  - PERSONAL PAPERS
    - Photograph of Lewis Einstein, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1528)
    - "What Europe Knew of China Three Hundred Years Ago", 1936 (Box 44, Folder 1529)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1530)